this salary is simply not comparable to
эта зарплата просто не сравнима с
American salaries. You just don’t
американскими зарплатами Просто вы не
compare their prices, other
сравнивайте у них же там и цены другие
prices Yes, absolutely different. I agree in
цены Да абсолютно другие Я согласен в
America the prices are cheaper if we take
Америке дешевле цены если мы возьмём
the phone, yours is more expensive if not if we
телефон у вас дороже если нет если мы
take it if we have food, look,
возьмём если мы питание де смотри
look how much food you have  you can
посмотрите сколько питания вы сможете
buy with your salary and how much an
купить на свою зарплату и сколько
American Do you want to compare this I have already
американец Вы хотите это сравнить Я уже
played this
игрался в эту
game Hello I am from the city of
игру Здравствуйте я из города
Khmelnitsky Where are you
Хмельницкий Вы откуда
from Leningrad Leningrad
с Ленинграда Ленинград А это
Where is this  st.
где это санкт-петербург А понял просто я
By the way, there were a lot of
радио слышал Кирову кстати очень много
streets from squares in the Soviet Union
улиц с площадей в Советском Союзе было
in all the republics, and what’s more, this
во всех республиках и причём что этот
man didn’t really
человек прямо так такового ничего не
do anything for politics there
сделал для для политики там пом больше
Moreover, he was just shot with a
того е его просто его просто застрелили
sawn-off shotgun. Yes, but Brezhnev Who wasn’t on the streets
обрез его Да а Брежнев Кто был не улиц
No, well, Brezhnev That’s later, look, they
Не ну Брежнева Это позже смотрите это ж
called the streets of those communists who
называли улицами тех коммунистов которые
were there when Brezhnev already that he
были там огого когда Брежнев уже что он
came already with everything ready, he didn’t do the
пришёл уже на всё готовое он не делал
World Revolution
Революции мировой
Yes, to me  I’m more interested in
Да мне мне больше интересно вот в
Leningrad, more precisely in modern
Ленинграде у вас точнее в современном
St. Petersburg, if I’m not
санкт-петербурге если я не
mistaken, there were the streets of Sofia Perovskaya and
ошибаюсь были улицы Софьи Перовской и
Vera Zasulich, one of them seems
Веры засулич одну из них вроде
renamed and the second one
переименовали а вторая
remained to be honest I don’t know Do you know
осталась честно сказать Не знаю А знаете
who they were Who they are Yes I don’t know Well there
кто это были Кто такие Да я не знаю Ну
was a terrorist organization
была террористическая организация
People’s will that’s what they are there
Народная воля такая они там бо
No well if you look at it like that if you
Не ну если так разобраться если так
look at it like that Any revolutions are made by
разобраться любые Революции делают
terrorists No well I understand correctly they
террористы Не ну я правильно понимаю
just do not do  Yes, what's the point? The
просто делают не делают Да что в са
point is that there will be deaths everywhere of any kind.
Смысл в том что везде смерти будут любой
There were and are revolutions and then cleanings
Революции были и есть и потом очистки
take place. No, I understand correctly
потом проходят Не ну я правильно понимаю
that it’s like in Leningrad. In modern
что как бы в Ленинграде В современном
St. Petersburg, yes, there are still
санкт-петербурге да до сих пор есть
streets  I
улицы именами
don’t know the names of the terrorists, to be honest, let’s say,
террористов не знаю честно говоря
I’ve never wondered about these, I
давайте я сечас никогда не задавался эти
wondered, but I’m interested in
задавался да интересно А мне интересно
St. Petersburg, Vera Zasulich Street
санкт-петербург улица Веры засулич
in St. Petersburg in the course of changes Yes, I’m
в санкт-петербурге по ходу перемен Да я
right now I’m here Just a second, now I’ll
вот сейчас я вот Секунду сейчас я
look in the navigator Sofia Perovskaya
навигаторе посмотрю Софии Перовской
Zasulich is
засулич уже
no longer here and Sophia  Perovskaya has already been renamed
нету а Софьи Перовской уже переименовали
to the horse small stable Oh this is already 100
в ко коню малое конюшина О это уже 100
years ago,
лет назад
here it is  here is a look at the street of Sofia Perovskaya in
вот а вот смотр улица Софии Перовской во
many cities of Russia there is in Astrakhan in
многих городах России есть в Астрахане в
Bryansk in
Брянске во
Vladivostok Sofia Perovskaya is so
Владивостоке Софья Перовская
interesting she
интересная
led the assassination of Emperor
такая руководила убийством императора
Alexander
Александра
II it is clear
II это понятно
now after every Revolution I see
теперь после каждой Революции вот вижу
yes in Voronezh there is in Yekaterinburg in the
да в Воронеже есть в Екатеринбурге в
verka in the kaza after every Revolution Yes it is
верке в каза после каждой Революции Да
not clear after  Every Revolution
не понятно после каждой Революции
Novgorod has such heroes, there are such heroes.
Новгород есть такие есть такие герои Не
No, the point is not that after the revolution,
ну суть же не в том что после революции
not after the revolution, as in, for example,
не после революции как вот например в
modern Russia can
современной России может могут
speak at the same time, look, we
одновременно говорить смотрите мы
named the
назвали
street in honor of the woman who
ээ улицу в честь женщины которая
organized the throwing of a bomb at the Tsar. Yes,
организовывала бросание бомбы в царя Да
and at the same time, we are for crying with a white
А при этом мы за плакати с белым
leaf, screw
листочком винти
white leaves, rolls, what is that? Well, for
белые листочки покаты это что Ну
example, if someone goes out on a single
например если кто-то выйдет на одиночный
picket, he will be tied up.
пикет его скрутят
Yes,  everywhere That is, I understand correctly
Да так везде То есть я правильно понимаю
that in modern Russia there are
что в современной России легальных
no legal political methods of struggle left
политических методов борьбы не осталось
and the authorities are pushing people to give birth to new ones.
и власть толкает людей на рождение новых
Vera Zasulich Sofia and the
Вер засулич Софии и
Perovskys all the time were in a kind of
перовских всё время были в роде
faith in their time which
веры в своё время которых использовали
people did not name the
люди не называют
streets
улиц улице называла новая
called the new government Question here you have in St. Petersburg Kiev in Kyiv this is a question You have not so long ago a girl named Daria damn forgot her last name blew up this Tatar dumplings according to Trepova Daria Trepova Yes, look, it turns out when Putin’s power is overthrown What do you think Is it necessary to name a street in St. Petersburg after Daria Trepova? Well, first of all, Daria Trepova is just a criminal  a terrorist
трепова - это просто уголовник террорист
who is just like Vera Zasulich,
который вот вот именно как Вера засулич
this is all
это это всё
with in Yes, secondly, the power will not
с во Да вото во-вторых власть не
change Well, look, when
поменяется Ну вот смотрите когда
they threw a bomb at Alexander II there, they also
Александра II там кидали бомбочкой тоже
said the power will not change, yes But
говорили власть не поменяется да А
somehow now other people are living here,
как-то сечас другие люди здесь живут уже
perhaps they are not living  But other people have
возможно живут не живут Но другие люди
other problems and so the question
другие проблемы и всё так оп вопрос
turns out that when Putin’s power falls,
получается что когда власть Путина падёт
Daria Trepova will historically become
то Дарья трепова исторически станет
a heroine. No. Why no, she
героиней нет Почему нет никогда она не
will never become a heroine because she will spend
станет героиней потому что она проведёт
her whole life in prison. So
всю свою жизнь в тюрме Так почему
why when there was a revolution in this year in this year there will be Vla me again look and who who in this year could say that there will be a February Revolution then an October Revolution that after all this year smart people lived only in big cities St. Petersburg St. Petersburg Moscow there Kyiv And on the periphery, to these people, who is in power there? Because people were just like that, now I already know everything, now the Internet is not like that, it’s all simple, especially since you know, I’m listening to the sun  even
тем более вы знаете ВС время слушаю даже
your politicians, too, just like that,
ваших политиков тоже вот просто так тубе
there you see it happens People are like another
там это смотришь бывает Люди как другой
planet to God so that here we have
планеты Богу такую что здесь у нас здесь
all the [ __ ] there they are all fine Here
вся Фигово там все они нормально Здесь
where here even I’ll tell you in
где здесь даже я вам скажу в
Russia from with it’s called Yes sometimes
России из с называется Да иногда вот
we come in the evenings he’s there something-  then talk
приходим вечерами он там что-то гутарить
and he really says that in Russia he
и он реально говорит что в России он
compares, for example, salary levels in
сравнивает например уровни зарплат в
America and salary levels in Russia
Америке и уровни зарплат в России
Andrey says how to live in such a
говорит Андрей как как с такими
rich resource gold oil
богатейшими ресурсами золото нефть
diamonds I
алмазы жить в такой
don’t know I have a good salary everything
как не знаю у меня хорошая зарплата всё
suits me how much is your
меня устраивает сколько у вас
salary  in rubles Yes, I’ll convert it into dollars,
зарплата в рублях Да я в доллары
divide it by
переведу поделю на
100 Well, approximately 120-130,000 rubles, that is,
100 Ну примерно 120-130 000 руб то есть
1,200 dollars Oh, I don’t know by 100 by 100,
1.200 долларов О я не знаю на 100 на 100
divide by 100, divide by 1,200
делим на 100 делим получаем 1.200
dollars That is, this salary is simply not
долларов То есть эта зарплата просто не
comparable with American salaries
сравнима с американскими зарплатами
You just don’t compare  They also have
Просто вы не сравниваете у них же там и
different prices there Yes, absolutely different I
цены другие цены Да абсолютно другие Я
agree in America the prices are cheaper if we
согласен в Америке дешевле цены если мы
take a phone  yours is more expensive if not
возьмём телефон у вас дороже если нет
if we take if we food de
если мы возьмём если мы питание де
look Look how much food you
смотри Смотрите сколько питания вы
can buy with your salary and
сможете купить на свою зарплату и
how much American You want to
сколько американец Вы хотите это
compare this I have already played this
сравнить Я уже игрался в эту
game I no
игру Я нет
yes Let's see for example Let's How
да Давайте посмотрим например Давайте
much meat can you buy in America with your
Сколько в Америке мяса можно на свою
salary  buy and how much in Russia for
зарплату купить и сколько в России на
yours Let's, yes, I have no idea
вашу Давайте да я понятия не имею
Let's try Yes, I'm not interested in
Давайте попробуем Да оно мне не интерес
why I'm not interested because it's a small thing in
почему не интересно потому что это мелоч
life,
жизнь
you know, I want with you, you said, you said
знаеш хочется с ты ты сказал ты сказал
that in America the prices are more expensive So I
что в Америке и цены дороже Так я же
want to look at the American's
хочу посмотреть американец на свою
salary  What volume of goods and services
зарплату Какой объём товаров и услуг
can you buy and you? One American can,
может купить и ты один американец может
and another cannot, and in Russia, too,
а другой не может так и в России также
one can, we’ll take the average
один может мы возьмём среднего
median Let’s compare some two,
медианного Давайте сравним каких-то дву
I’ll tell you this, I’ll tell you this, I’m tired,
я вам так скажу я вам так скажу надоело
tired if a person is not If a person can
надоело если чело нет Если человек может
earn  if he is not lazy he will live
заработать если он не лентяй он проживёт
in any country Absolutely true, absolutely
в любой стра Абсолютно верно абсолютно
agree yes But if a person can
согласен да Но если человек может
earn money Yes and he is not lazy in an
заработать Да и не лентяя он в
African country he will be at a certain
Африканской стране будет на определённом
level of development in a post-Soviet country at
уровне развития в постсоветской на
another in a capitalist one  developed on the
другом в капиталистической развито на
third this is also if you are a fisherman You are a
третьем это также если ты рыбак Ты
cool Fisherman But if you wait don’t
крутой Рыбак Но если ты подожди не
interrupt if you if you are cool if you are a
перебивай если ты если ты крутой если ты
cool Fisherman Yes and you fish with
крутой Рыбак Да и ты ловишь у тебя
fashionable fishing rods you hook there eat but you
удочки модные ты там подсека ешь но ты
fish where there is almost no fish you something
ловишь там где рыбы почти нет ты что-то
Suppose you will have more fish than the
слови ты будешь иметь больше рыбы чем
lazy Fisherman, but you will have little fish
лентяй Рыбак Но у тебя будет мало рыбы
if you catch where there is more of it under the
если ты ловишь там где её больше при
same conditions, you will have more
таких же условиях ты будешь иметь больше
fish than the neighboring Fisherman, but more than
рыбы чем соседний Рыбак но больше чем
the one who  catches ore in an empty pond And if you
тот кто ловит в пустом руду А если ты
fish in a pond where everything is
будешь ловить в пруду где рыбой всё
teeming with fish, you will have even more
кишит да ты будешь иметь ещё больше
fish, it is natural that the Fisherman who is
рыбы естественно что Рыбак который
lazy will
лентяй он будет во всех трёх
have little fish in all three Ponds Naturally,
Прудах мало рыбы иметь Естественно что
the one who spins will have
тот кто крутится будет иметь в одном и
more in the same pond  fish than the one who is
том же пруду больше рыбы чем тот кто
lazy, but if we compare two
лентяй но если мы сравним двух
identical fishermen who work with
одинаковых рыбаков которые работают со
their fishing rods, feeding supplies Yes, but
своей удочкой закидушки подкормки Да но
one is in a good pond and the other in a poor one,
один в хорошем пруду а другой в бедном
then they, however,  with the same investment of the
то они при однаково одинаковом вложении
time of their labor, they will receive
времени своего своего труда они получат
disproportionately different output: someone is going
несоизмеримо разный выхлоп кто-то
to catch crucian carp, I look, I’m catching
наловить карасиков идут я смотри жменю
crucian carp And someone, look at the pike I
карасей А кто-то смотри какую я щуку
caught Yes, and so is Russia. Tell me
поймал Да так вот и Россия Скажите
why Russia should change power,
почему Россия должна власть поменяться я
don’t forget about the power, it won’t
не забудь уже про власть она не
change.  with a mindset like yours,
поменяется с таким мышлением как у вас
it won’t change at all. Yes, I’m
она вообще не поменяется Да я тебя
asking you. You said, look, don’t
спрашиваю Вот ты сказал смотри не
interrupt. Look, you said that in  In America the
перебивай Смотри ты сказал что в Америке
prices are more expensive I want I want here you have
там цены дороже Я хочу я хочу вот у тебя
Come on now We're talking about your thinking
Давай сейчас Мы про про твоё мышление
tell Andrei My name is say like people
скажи Андрей Меня зовут скажи как люди
no Shut your mouth Listen Shut your mouth and don't
нет Закрой рот Послушай Закрой рот и не
interrupt Look tell me who can
перебивай Смотри скажи кто больше Может
buy goods and services with your salary more
на свою зарплату купить товары и услуг
You or you are an American
ты или американец ты
boring
нудно здравствуйте
hello Hello Is that a flag hanging behind you
Здравствуйте Мне это у вас флаг сзади
or what? No, it’s me, draw a wall,
висит или что Нет это я стену порисовать
that’s a wall, I have a liquid wall Haven’t you
это стена у меня жидкая стена Вы что не
seen such liquid walls?  It’s clear that with the
видели такие жидкие стены понятно с
gel shell the partition is still
гелевой оболочкой перегородка она ещ
hanging unevenly, so it’s unlikely to be a wall,
неровно висит поэтому вряд ли это стена
most likely some kind of curtain. Well,
скорее всего какая-то штора Ну ладно
never mind. It’s your right. It’s clear, and you have it too. Do you
неважно Это Ваше право Ясно а у вас тоже
also have ra or not? no, both of them, well,
У вас тоже ра или нет нет это обое ну
touch it; it’s interesting; the earphone will
Потрогай интересно наушник будет
definitely be removed;
снять точно
really, really; Yes  I
действительно действительно Да я са
was just there There was a white wall, it
просто была Была белая стена она меня
really irritated me I myself was just a
очень раздражала я Сам просто белая
big white wall Beya, originally from Barnaul, I’ve been living
стена большая Бея родом из Барнаула живу
in Finland for 18 years now  2 years
в Финляндии уже 18 лет через 2 года
will be before where are you from so this is the flag
будет дто Вы откуда так это флаг
of Finland no yes this is
Финляндии нет да это ла
Finland asked you for some kind of flag
Финляндии спросила у вас какой-то флаг
Yes I understand now I’m from Moscow from Moscow I’m
Да Поняла теперь я из Москвы из Москвы
a native or a newcomer, but what’s a
коренная или понаехавшая да что ж такое
native in the third generation will arrange
коренная в третьем поколении устроит
great-grandmother and great-grandfather are also buried
прабабушка и прадедушка тоже похоронены
here and the fourth  the generation from where
здесь а четвёртое поколение откуда
they came to Moscow from Pyatigorsk about then to
приехало в Москву из Пятигорска о то в
these Caucasus Yes, what is this, well, the Caucasus And
эти Кавказ Да а что это ну Кавказ А мне
so far they told me  Vladi Kavkaz and Caucasus
пока сказали Влади Кавказ да Кавказ
Mineralnye Vody I understand you are an
Минеральные Воды я понял Вы по
Armenian by nationality Armenian I
национальности кто армянка армянка Я так
thought so, I think I’ll clarify because sometimes you make
и да подумал думаю уточню потому что
a mistake and for example you will say you are an
бывает ошибёшься да например скажешь вы
Armenian, an Azerbaijani man Yes,
армянка человек азербайджанец Да и та
damn it, or vice versa. It happens, you know
блин или наоборот Бывает такое знаете
how to distinguish Armenians from other Caucasian
как отличить армян от других кавказских
peoples, especially from  very different
народов особенно от други очень потому
because Armenians also have different subtypes and
что у армян тоже разные есть подтипы и у
no wait wait the Armenians are very
нет подождите подождите у армян очень
close  the eyes are set and the Georgians,
близко посажены глаза а у грузин
on the contrary, are very far away, just
наоборот очень далеко вот просто
remember this and then you will check, you
запомните это и будете потом проверять
will be surprised that I’m right, I’m an Armenian or a
удивитесь что я права так Я армянин или
Georgian, I
грузин
look more like a Russian, you want to insult me
больше на русского похож оскорбить меня
Why does it look like a Russian, damn it,
Почему похоже на русского блин
Russified like a Russian, I’m not Russian, I
обрусевший на русского по Я не русский я
’m from Barnaul Yes, but  I’m not Russian
родом из Барнаула Да но я не русский У
My father is Altai, yes And my mother is also from
меня отец алтаец да А мама тоже с
the Caucasus, my mother
Кавказа мама
Vizh Altai is nothing, well, my
виж Алтайского ничего ви Ну вот у меня
mother’s is more Avarka, my mother is from where  Kavka
мамина больше аварка мама откуда кавка
Avarka from Makhachkala Well, it’s near
аварка из Махачкалы Ну там возле ма
Dagestan, that is, it’s not Maha itself, there
Дагестан то есть там не сам Маха там
was some kind of aul there, I don’t know exactly
какой-то аул был я не знаю там точно
who you were there,
этих вы там были когда-нибудь
or Well, because it’s from Barla It’s very
или Ну потому что это от барла Это очень
far away, it’s understandable, it’s considered
далеко понятное считается
from where I have nieces  travels a lot, they
изх мест у меня племянниц очень много
love this business, there are the most
ездит очень любят это дело там
interesting excursions, the most interesting EU
интереснейшие экскурсии интереснейшие ЕС
to see everything, in short, interesting They
всё посмотреть короче интересно Они
were able to make this land attractive,
смогли сделать привлекательную эту землю
it’s cool, that is, from Moscow there are a lot of people there
прикольно то есть из Москвы там много
now going to Dagestan on excursions yes
сейчас в Дагестана едут на экскурсии да
yes  to relax on the Caspian Sea to
да отдохнуть на Каспийском море
relax Yes, no, they don’t get to the sea.
отдохнуть Да нет до моря не добираются
Usually in the inland territory, she then
Обычно по внутренне территори она потом
also writes, as it were, travel notes, very
ещё пишет как бы путевые заметки очень
interesting, always so I understood. My
интересные всегда так понял У меня
parents stayed in Barnaul. Yes, that’s it. And why did
родители остались в Барнауле Да такое А
you leave? I went to look for a better life.
вы что уехали поехал лучшую жизнь искать
Well, stop, you were  once in
Ну вы давайте стоп вы были когда-то в
Barnaul in Barnaul there was no Finland,
Барнауле в Барнауле не была Финляндии
if only yes Now if you were
была вот если бы да Вот если бы вы были
in Barnaul and Finland you wouldn’t
в Барнауле и Финляндии у вас бы не
have a question Why did you travel from
возникало вопроса Почему ехал из
Barnaul And now  in Barnaul it’s just as
Барнаула А сейчас в Барнауле так же
bad as it was then or something has changed
плохо как и тогда или что-то изменилось
something has changed Yes,
что-то изменилось Да появился интернет
better quality Internet has appeared and so it’s
более качественный да такой а так
really poverty poverty Well, my
реально бедность нищета Ну вот у меня у
father’s pension is 20,000 rubles He’s
отца пенсия 20.000 руб Ему не
missing 200
хватает 200
dollars So we have a communal apartment
долларов Так у нас у нас коммуналка
kopecks compared with Western countries
копейки сравнивать с западными странами
stop stop how much do you have in Moscow pension
стоп стоп сколько у вас в Москве пенсия
or salary I have 30 30,000 rubles yes this is a
или зарплата у меня 30 30.000 руб да это
pension or salary pension How do you
пенсия или зарплата пенсия Как вы
survive  it’s
выживает
very simple, I still have left, I still
очень даже просто мне ещё остаётся я ещё
help my grandchildren, I also have a dacha for which
внукам помогаю меня ещё дача на которые
crazy money is being poured here, crazy
бешеные деньги выливаются сюда бешеные
money. This is how much per month. I mean, well,
деньги Это сколько в месяц В смысле Ну
you’re
вы
pouring in, this year
вливает вот в этом году 150.000
you spent 150,000 on sheds because they
потратила на навесы потому что они
sank 150,000 - that’s your five pensions.
просели 150.000 - это ваших пять пенсий
Well,  that Yes, they still have money left, we still have
Ну и что Да они остаются деньги у нас ещ
plenty of subsidies, wait and look at
полно субсидий намер Подождите
the cost of the phone, I have a
п пови стоимости телефона у меня
subsidy. For an apartment, how much how much do you
субсидия За квартиру сколько сколько вы
pay for  product that's how much you spend on food
платите за продукт вот сколько вы на еду
per month Yes, as much as I want
тратите в месяц Да сколько хочу столько
I spend quickly, well, it turns out that I'm from 30,000
Я трачу ско получается ну меня от 30.000
I don't spare money we have good
я я я не жалею деньги у нас хорошие
stores nearby I don't go to the most Virgos
магазины рядом я хожу не самые Девы Вот
I'm interested yes you get a 30,000
мне интересно да вы получаете 30.000
pension Yes you don't spare money  How much
пенсии Да вы не жалеете деньги Сколько у
money do you have left per month? Well, look.
Вас остаётся в месяц денег ну смотрите
Well, there are thousands left.
Ну тысяч остаётся тысяч остаётся да да
you just
останется 120 000 а вы 150 только на
threw away 150 for the dacha, I still have a deposit of
дачу выкинули у меня ещё есть вклад по
20% per annum from which I get a
20% годовых с которых я получаю
good monthly increase, I won’t
ежемесячно хороший прибавок я не буду
say this is commercial information. I understand.
говорить это коммерческая информация
That is, it turns out that
Поня То есть получается у
you live on 20,000 rubles per month,
вас Вы живёте на 20.000 руб в месяц на
200 dollars this food
200 долларов это питание
means utilities for me  costs about
значит коммуналка мне обходится где-то в
5000 all with internet No, not more,
5000 вся с интернетом Нет не п побольше
probably 5500 these are apartments, all these
наверно 5500 это квартиры все эти
stuff, light and internet with TV
причиндалы свет и интернет с телевизором
So the rest is spent on food somewhere on
Так остальное уходит на еду где-то в
average per week I spend Well, even being
среднем в неделю я трачу Ну доже быть
there once a week I order groceries at
там раз в неделю заказываю продукты
home Well, well, sometimes it comes out to five But this is a
надом Ну ну пять иногда выходит Но это
rarity in a month, since it’s already a month,
редкость в меся так это уже в месяц
it won’t be 20, but 41 is already
то не 20 получатся е 41 уже уже всё
more anyway  You spent 20,000 together
равно больше 20.000 вы потратили вместе
with utilities, look at 4,000 rubles each,
с коммунал кой смотри по по 4.000 руб
that’s Why are you going, some little thing, I
это А что вы идите какую-то мелочь
don’t know, 40 dollars a month, here it is  Do
какую-то не знаю 40 долларов в месяц вот
you calculate according to your prices or according to
э А вы по своим ценам считаете или по
ours What are your prices first Look
нашему Какие вы сначала цены Посмотрите
then we will be shortchanged
тогда мы будем обсчитывают
and in Moscow Well I understood in Moscow Well I don’t know
а в Москве Ну понял в Москве Ну не знаю
that’s 40,000 a week divided by 7 it
это 40.000 в неделю разделим на 7 это
turns out uh 600 rubles somewhere a day 600
получается ээ 600 руб где-то в день 600
rubles I once a week  I’m ordering groceries I
руб я раз в неделю заказываю продукты Я
explained it to you once in Ned, well that’s right
же вам объяснила раз в Неде ну правильно
I’m getting the daily ration you get 600
Я получаю вот дневной рацион у вас 600
rubles it turns out I don’t count I don’t
руб получается это я не считаю я не
count the daily ration I ordered
считаю дневной рацион Я заказала
groceries  cooked soup I have enough for 3
продукты сварила суп Мне хватает на 3
days fried cutlets I have enough for 4 days
дня пожарила котлет Мне хватает на 4 дня
How do you count cutlets per cutlet
Как вы считаете котлет на котлетку
count or something or Lot I The fact is
рассчитывать что ли или на Лота я Дело в
that I am a professor of mathematics at the
том что я профессор математики в
university I took 7 days to eat
университете я взял м вает 7 дней кушать
4000 rubles that’s 600 per day  rubles
4000 руб это на день получается 600 руб
for breakfast lunch dinner That turns out to be
на завтрак обед ужин Это получается по
200 rubles per meal 2
200 руб на приём пищи 2
dollars what do you
доллара что вы
eat a pack of cottage cheese costs 40
едите пачка творога стоит 40
rubles a pack of cottage cheese is enough for 2  of the day for
руб творог пачки хватает на 2 дня на
breakfast, an
завтрак
egg, lavash, instead of bread, I buy feta cheese,
яйцо лаваш я покупаю вместо хлеба брынза
cheese, that’s all Breakfast, lunch, soup, some kind of
сыр это всё Завтрак обед суп какое-то
meat dish, I usually buy chicken, Yeah,
мясное блюдо я обычно курицу покупаю Угу
and you buy fruits there. Yes, of course,
а фрукты покупаете себе там Да конечно
I have them now, I just ate
Вот у меня сейчас стоят только что съела
this Mango. We now sell cheap Mangoes.
этот Манго У нас сейчас Манго дешёвые
apparently they brought a lot, very
продают их видно много завезли очень
cheap, uh, it turns out a week is shorter than
дешёвые ээ получается в неделю короче
4,000 rubles 40 dollars yes Well, I’m saying, I
4.000 руб 40 долларов да Ну я и говорю я
don’t say I can, 3,000 I can  to
же не кажу могу 3.000 могу на опять
order again, choose cottage cheese 40 rubles costs Well, I
заказа выбирите творог 40 руб стоит Ну я
buy 40 yes for 40 rubles, yes it’s good for
покупаю 40 да по 40 руб да это хорошая
me for D for two times half a dollar is enough
мне на Д на два раза хватает полдоллара
not something
не это что-то
you And where is it I’m interested to see
вы А где это я мне интересно посмотреть
in which store the cottage cheese is 40 rubles I’m
в каком магазине творог 40 руб мне
interested In which ones  store there is such a
интересно В каких магазине есть такой
store
магазинчик
tastevil there is also Magnit store there is also
вкусвил есть ещё Магнит магазин есть ещё
Pyaterochka And how many grams of this
Пятёрочка И сколько сколько грамм этого
cottage cheese is 100 rubles Oh I think 400 grams
творога 100 рубле Ой я думаю грамм 400
probably oh no no probably  300 250 g
наверное ой нет нет наверное 300 250 г
250 g this is more like butter a pack
250 г это такая паче как масло пачка
similar to butter Yes
похожая на масло Да
no
нет
now so what for 40 rubles this is some kind of thing
сейчас так какой за 40 руб это какой-то
at all I don’t see such Curds for 40
вообще я не вижу таких Творогов за 40
rubles well look through the assortment
руб ну полазить по по ассортименту
you will find curds there are some in jars
найдёте творожки есть таких в баночках
like not  yoghurts and curds
как бы типа не йогурты а творожки
Wait, it’s me. I understood correctly, you
Подождите это я Я правильно понял вы
are buying expired products that I
просроченные продукты покупаете которые
already buy products in stock, therefore they
уже покупаю продукты в запас поэтому
are expired  I can’t buy it I’m buying it
просроченные покупать не могу я покупаю
for a week which ones may be expired If
на неделю какие они могу просрочены Если
for a week you can show me this
на неделю можете показать вот этот
cottage cheese for 40 rubles I want to find this
творог за 40 руб Я хочу найти вот какой
cottage cheese you buy for 40 now I
творог вы покупаете за 40 сейчас не
can’t Yala now what can I show you now
смогу Яла сечас что я вам могу сейчас
I can show you now
показать Я могу вам сейчас показать
the avocado you want  I’ll show you the apples, I can
авокадо хотите покажу яблоки могу
show you the tomatoes, cucumbers, what’s
показать помидоры огурцы что меня сейчас
in the refrigerator right now, you can show me the receipt,
в холодильнике е може можете чек
that’s the receipt, that’s really interesting.
показать вот чек интересно действительно
No, what am I saving or something for your
Нет а что я сохраняю что ли для вашего
conversation? How do you imagine I’m getting
разговора Как вы себе представляете я
the receipt?  I’m saving for I want to talk to you
чек сохраняю для хочу поговорить с вами
in the trash can, I can climb but I won’t
в помойке могу полазить но я не буду
do it and then the groceries I
этим заниматься и потом продукты Я
ordered on Wednesday from Wednesday I’ve already
заказывала в среду со среды всё уже
finished everything and the receipts are all gone left [ __ ]
доела и и чеки все ушли осталось суку
me If it’s similar Let’s see it
меня Коли по схо Давайте посмотрим
turns out Even if we accept that you
получается Даже если мы примем что вы
eat 4,000  rubles a week, that’s four
едите 4.000 руб в неделю это за четыре
in 28 days, that’s 16,000, plus
за 28 дней получается 16.000 да плюс ещё
2 more days. In short, it works out. In total,
2 дня Короче это получается В общем 17
you have 17 17 18,000 rubles  it turns out 17 Yes,
17 18.000 руб у вас получается 17 Да
17,000 rubles will be spent per month on food
17.000 руб уйдёт в месяц на еду
5 s for a communal apartment, this is already 22.5 out of
5 с по на коммуналку это уже 22,5 из
30,000 You have 7,500 left and you have no
30.000 у Вас остаётся 7500 и Вам ни
Clothes, but it turns out nothing in short,
Одежды да получается ни короче другое
nothing else, no travel, but you ride for free,
ничего ни проезд а ездите вы бесплатно
yes for free, pensioners ride for free
да бесплатно пенсионеры едут бесплатно
Pony on any  the type of transport on the train is
Поня на любом виде транспорта поезде мне
enough for me, a taxi is enough, and by train the
ещё на такси хватает а на поезде на
electric train is also free, so
электричке тоже бесплат так в другие
you go on vacation to other regions now  I don’t
регионы Вы ездите отдыхать сейчас уже
have a problem with my knee anymore, you wo
нет у меня проблемы с коленом не
n’t go to this nude. Why wo
на эту ню не поедете А что на такую
n’t you go on such a pension? You don’t have any
пенсию Вы не поедете у вас не остаётся
money left for the trip. Yes, I’ll go anywhere,
денег на поездку Да поеду я куда угодно
I have enough money. Your dad gets
мне денег хватает вот ваш папа получает
20 and your mom. How much does mom get
20 а мама Сколько получает мама
15 35 for two?  They don’t
15 35 на двоих Им не
have enough No, of course I send it to them Yes, I
хватает Нет конечно я им высылаю Да я
send it I help I don’t know what’s
высылаю помогаю не знаю
amazing about sub
удивительное об суб
I pay back he transfers some
перет плачу обратно переводит какую-то
amount of about 2 I look I googled
сумму порядка 2 я вот смотрите Я гуглил
this to my taste Vela  yes, the cheapest
в этом во вкус веле да э самый дешёвый
cottage cheese 200 g 150
творог 200 г 150
rubles It seems to me that you are disingenuous about 40 you
руб Мне кажется Вы лукавить про 40 вы
are looking at not cottage cheese but curds I said
смотрите Не творог а творожки Я сказала
in these, otherwise you are looking at the wrong thing You are
вот в этих а то вы не то смотрите Вы
like cottage cheese I understand everything, you
типа творожок Всё я понял вы как
buy curd mass no curd
творожково массу покупаете нет творожная
mass is not that  and that cottage cheese is
масса - это не то а что творожок - это
a type of yogurt, just whipped cottage cheese in
типа йогурта только взбитый творог в
a jar, like this jar, in short, it’s not
баночке такой вот баночку короче это не
cottage cheese, not  Cottage cheese is some kind of mixture,
творог не Творог это какая-то смесь
it’s not clear, but there is a jar, you can have the composition
непонятно а есть баночка можете состав
No, that’s all I have Sour cream, just
Да нет всё вот у меня Сметана только
now there’s a jar in the trash somewhere in
сейчас помойке лежит баночку где-то в
the back I can’t find the composition, it’s churned cottage
глубине не найду состав это там сбитый
cheese And there’s some other jam underneath, I
творог А внизу ещё какой-то Джем лежит я
don’t know how to explain it to you  called
не знаю как вам объяснить называется
Miracle curd dial Look at the
Чудо творожок наберите Посмотрите
miracle curd Now look Yes dessert
чудо-творожок Сейчас посмо Да десерт
dessert Miracle curd miracle curd
десерт Чудо творожок чудо-творожок
that is, because it’s not yours Well,
то есть потому что это не тво Ну не
cottage cheese can’t  it’s like this,
может творог такой у
but it’s small. This is like a
а то это маленький Вот это такой как
child’s, not small. It’s enough for
типа детский не маленький Мне хватает на
one time. In addition, I already make culinary
один раз Кроме того Так уже кулинарные
delights, I make cottage cheese myself, I buy it.
изыски я сама делаю творог я покупаю
Maybe you don’t know if you buy
Может быть вы не знаете если купить
kefir and freeze it, so wait,
кефир и заморозить его так вот подождите
I wanted something for you-  then say Come on, if you
я хотела вам что-то сказать Давай если
buy kefir, freeze it, kefir,
купить кефир заморозить его кефир
in my opinion, costs about 80 rubles or something,
по-моему стоит сколько 80 руб что ли
freeze it later Well, just
заморозить его потом Ну только
freeze it well and then put
заморозить хорошенько а потом положить
it in a colander, then in the morning Anna, by the way, it’s worth it
его в дуршлаг то утро ання кстати стоит
now in the morning you will have cottage cheese for
сейчас то утром у вас будет творог на
two servings lower cottage cheese opened the
две порции нижней творож открыл сайт
Vkusvilla website Yes, here is the miracle curd pear
вкусвилла Да вот творожок чудо груша
peach 100 g 78 rubles no no 44 I buy
персик 100 г 78 руб не нет 44 я покупаю
look again everything has merged woman
смотри ещё раз всё баба слилось
I would open it 200 g cottage cheese 40 rubles
б я же открываю 200 г творог 40 руб
I think it’s less than  half a dollar
думаю это что меньше чем полдоллара
something for cottage cheese like maybe it's from a bull
что-то за творог типа Может это с быка
cottage cheese
творог
like shorter but no longer cottage cheese but  cottage cheese
типа короче а уже не творог а творожок
like yogurt, something like that mixed together, this is
типа йогурт чтото такое намешано это
[ __ ], in short, and not and not 40 rubles, yes And
фигня вот короче и не и не 40 руб да А
200 g, but 100 g, 78 rubles, this is in short,
200 г а вот 100 г 78 руб это короче
some kind of
какая-то
[ __ ] with cottage cheese for Yes, God knows, in the World Cup it’s
Фигня творожком по Да Боже знаете в ЧМ
interesting, now specially underground in
интересно вот сейчас специально подзем в
m interesting Russia They
м интересно России Они
live  they live in
живут живут в
poverty and they sing about their poverty
нищете и они воспевают свою нищету
instead of honestly saying damn Yes,
вместо того чтобы честно сказать блин Да
I live in Moscow in the capital of the richest
я живу в Москве в столице богатейшей
country with oil and gas  diamonds Yes, and I live
страны с нефтью газом алмазами Да и живу
poor, I live poorer than Fin, I can’t
бедно живу беднее чем Фин я не могу себе
afford normal
позволить нормальное
food. We don’t talk about what there. Yes, she’s
питание Мы же не говорим там про что Да
still got cottage cheese. Yes, why?
она творожок там ещё ещё Да почему
If we
Если мы
look at other countries, they have a better
смотрим другие страны да у них лучший
standard of living, and the Russians, instead of
уровень жизни а россияне вместо того
saying Yes,  we are [ __ ] Here we are in
чтобы сказать Да у нас фигня Вот мы в
Ukraine What are we saying Yes here We want to
Украине Что говорим Да у нас Мы хотим
move into the European Commonwealth We
двигаться в Европейское Содружество Мы
want to move towards these standards Yes and the
хотим к этим стандартам подвигаться Да а
Russians are sitting in a swamp But no ours are
россияне сидят в болоте Та нет наши
best of all
лучше всего
this dava
это дава
na th Instagram I don’t know  for what is it
на й Instagram Я не знаю для чого це то
for you there to marvel at the oce face and for
для тоб там дивитись на оце фейс а для
you one or two or three clicks Ale you trime
тебе оди два або три клика Але ты тримае
me and I will be kaza in me there A bunch of fouls
мене и я буду каза в мене там Купа фолов
and in me there will be a cool one robiti but
и в мене буде класный найб робити но
cool video message on th Instagram Popik
крут вдео пись на й Instagram Попик
Andriy
Андрий
So come on  I'm checking you
Так давай я тебя чекаю
out
с